{"bd5aa5ee-672e-4d60-8502-6ed78558579b":{"question":"Definition of an admixture is: _______","answer":"materials other than water, aggregate, or hydraulic cement used as an ingredient of concrete before or during it's mixture to modify its properties","chapter":"01: Design & Control Of Concrete Mixtures"},"5c08b986-1653-4e13-8c63-bf025d36d760":{"question":"Which of the following is not a reason for using admixtures in concrete? ____","answer":"other than listed","chapter":"01: Design & Control Of Concrete Mixtures"},"0da1e334-af5a-4a69-94c0-ebaf63fab4da":{"question":"High range water reducers conforming to ASTMC 1017 making a low slum concrete easily workable:","answer":"superplasticers","chapter":"01: Design & Control Of Concrete Mixtures"},"1f2680a6-41fe-4341-bb0a-e8207ecae463":{"question":"Plasticizers provide how much workability?","answer":"30 to 60 minutes","chapter":"01: Design & Control Of Concrete Mixtures"},"8d8ec9a0-7b0c-4c9e-8bda-108286d9339b":{"question":"Slows down the process of curing in concrete ____","answer":"retarders","chapter":"01: Design & Control Of Concrete Mixtures"},"87b77a62-47c1-4b85-9f02-75ceeefca832":{"question":"How does air content impact the slump of concrete?","answer":"can be placed with lower slump","chapter":"01: Design & Control Of Concrete Mixtures"},"5df9975b-34fd-425f-9471-44872d2cf810":{"question":"Most widely used method of removing air pockets from concrete after it is placed ______","answer":"vibration","chapter":"01: Design & Control Of Concrete Mixtures"},"eba8ddaf-8a00-4cdd-ae81-16aafcce88e0":{"question":"Which of the following concrete joints allows for both vertical and horizontal movement?","answer":"Isolation","chapter":"01: Design & Control Of Concrete Mixtures"},"99dc4161-28d0-4796-9bc2-e575069ae7c0":{"question":"Shortly after concrete is cast, volume can change. Early changes, within _____ hours, can influence the volume changes and crack the formation.","answer":"24","chapter":"01: Design & Control Of Concrete Mixtures"},"5660a459-6820-4c28-b2f0-9af434dcbd88":{"question":"What should be added to concrete that will be exposed to freezing and thawing cycles and de-icing chemicals?","answer":"Entrained Air","chapter":"01: Design & Control Of Concrete Mixtures"},"e6848170-9c2a-4705-9647-e4e710a22381":{"question":"Concrete can normally be placed within _____ after mixing","answer":"90 minutes","chapter":"01: Design & Control Of Concrete Mixtures"},"52e1c7c8-d6c8-4d1c-8d67-b577d078abcf":{"question":"The most widely used method of consolidating concrete is ________","answer":"vibration","chapter":"01: Design & Control Of Concrete Mixtures"},"903be5ef-8cb4-4fd0-8583-2f8c9c1f56b5":{"question":"Method used to provide a slip--resistant surface on exterior concrete:","answer":"vibration","chapter":"01: Design & Control Of Concrete Mixtures"},"a3b340c7-f33f-4934-a7fd-29a2ee77a22a":{"question":"Joint used to induce controlled cracking at preselected locations:","answer":"contraction joint","chapter":"01: Design & Control Of Concrete Mixtures"},"b0d73403-2a0f-41e3-a492-bffe232bf4a7":{"question":"Concrete will continue to gain strength with age provided it remains moist or has a relative humidity above ______%.","answer":"80","chapter":"01: Design & Control Of Concrete Mixtures"},"321c3110-7ce1-4dff-9b7f-d8c259a77617":{"question":"Other than water-cement ratio, which of the following impacts the strength of concrete?","answer":"Age","chapter":"01: Design & Control Of Concrete Mixtures"},"81bd959e-22e4-422d-bd96-4378920e66c7":{"question":"Air-entrained concrete with a low water-cement ratio and an air content of _____% will withstand a great number of cycles of freezing and thawing.","answer":"5 - 8","chapter":"01: Design & Control Of Concrete Mixtures"},"c80a764c-b23c-49f2-8a17-e010be4c741a":{"question":"What type of cement is typically used in concrete if not specified?","answer":"Type 1","chapter":"01: Design & Control Of Concrete Mixtures"},"e9ce2514-5975-4ae1-b411-d4be13a497cb":{"question":"Cement used when the forms need to be removed fast:","answer":"Type 3","chapter":"01: Design & Control Of Concrete Mixtures"},"d981a95b-2881-4ae6-85be-a50f964ed0de":{"question":"Type of cement used to minimize heat from hydration:","answer":"Type 4","chapter":"01: Design & Control Of Concrete Mixtures"},"f5eca2f1-b2e8-49bc-8eb4-6e7fd9cb4996":{"question":"To achieve improved concrete properties, the most widely used supplementary cementious material is _________","answer":"Fly Ash","chapter":"01: Design & Control Of Concrete Mixtures"},"fada4df0-3f84-47c7-bed3-80de0dfe4c7b":{"question":"When concrete is exposed to deicing chemicals, the maximum amount of allowable slag in percent of total cementious material by weight is ____ %.","answer":"50%","chapter":"01: Design & Control Of Concrete Mixtures"},"82d4a00c-9690-47a8-9f04-95ca6be09138":{"question":"________ adversely affects concrete if contained in mixing water.","answer":"algae","chapter":"01: Design & Control Of Concrete Mixtures"},"b0f9f1f9-59c4-4f88-91c6-d94e1eaf8bfc":{"question":"The mass or weight of aggregate required to fill a container of a specific unit volume is referred to as __________","answer":"bulk density","chapter":"01: Design & Control Of Concrete Mixtures"},"93a61b32-b9ca-4f55-a67b-133f39e6d894":{"question":"Concrete cylinder tests are used to ________.","answer":"estimate strength at a given time","chapter":"01: Design & Control Of Concrete Mixtures"},"eb7ae2ef-1a21-48b3-9b97-fd81c3176114":{"question":"For concrete to set quickly, Type ____ concrete should be used to produce high early strength.","answer":"3","chapter":"01: Design & Control Of Concrete Mixtures"},"0bcbb9ba-7498-4cdb-90e5-4f3d0f52dedb":{"question":"A characteristic of air-entrapment is it __________","answer":"makes concrete more workable","chapter":"01: Design & Control Of Concrete Mixtures"},"bd94eb60-1486-4d70-b9ff-c2388a33ac77":{"question":"Fly ash can be used in the calculation of minimum cement content for a concrete mix when ______","answer":"allowed by specifier","chapter":"01: Design & Control Of Concrete Mixtures"},"ebdb8093-fcd0-4902-93b0-6d15c19e16f9":{"question":"The maximum allowed delivery time for ready-mix concrete is _______","answer":"90 minutes","chapter":"01: Design & Control Of Concrete Mixtures"},"e26e60ba-3c0e-449d-96e0-ca3a8e8332d0":{"question":"Types of foundation generally specified when the allowable bearing capacity of the soil is very low to great depths ","answer":"Mat, Raft, and Floating","chapter":"01: Design & Control Of Concrete Mixtures"},"b648bef2-d75b-4eb0-9e5d-1543d12287f5":{"question":"The best kind of nails to use for nailing kickers, blocks, or braces where nails must be removed when the forms are stripped are ______","answer":"Double Headed","chapter":"01: Design & Control Of Concrete Mixtures"},"3a5d46f6-3043-4034-bb33-2be443f42817":{"question":"Safety factor for form ties is _____","answer":"2 : 1","chapter":"01: Design & Control Of Concrete Mixtures"},"893fb1e7-49fb-49ed-b57e-c8b1dabe14f5":{"question":"What would reduce the lateral pressure on concrete forms?","answer":"Slower rate of placing","chapter":"01: Design & Control Of Concrete Mixtures"},"18728a8c-1b39-4c3c-b16f-639639629b23":{"question":"What would reduce the lateral pressure on concrete forms?","answer":"Slower rate of placing","chapter":"01: Design & Control Of Concrete Mixtures"},"c1c61fc0-4017-4d06-aa00-aca1abec04a7":{"question":"In the absence of an engineer or time. criteria isn't available, the recommendations for the length of time that form work should remain in place is when ______","answer":"air temp is above 50 degrees F","chapter":"01: Design & Control Of Concrete Mixtures"},"969247ec-7757-4bf4-abd8-c37cc107ecba":{"question":"The main purpose for steel reinforcement is to resist _______","answer":"tensile forces","chapter":"01: Design & Control Of Concrete Mixtures"},"cb0557ec-0da1-460b-a19e-d06eb719f263":{"question":"Placing drawings for reinforcement show _________.","answer":"details for fabrication and placing of rebar","chapter":"01: Design & Control Of Concrete Mixtures"},"289f470b-04c6-400f-ab4c-b2d0640aa709":{"question":"a #5 R-bar has the following characteristics ________","answer":".625\" diameter, .31 sq in, 1.043 lbs/ft","chapter":"01: Design & Control Of Concrete Mixtures"},"d2b064a8-d1e0-43fa-92b5-cfab3c353cfb":{"question":"Rebar is required to be marked to identify","answer":"mill #, size # type, grade #","chapter":"01: Design & Control Of Concrete Mixtures"},"166ae06d-33ae-42a1-876d-decf33db0bb5":{"question":"The effect of lowering the top bar or raising the lower bar 1/2\" more than specified in a 6\" slab is ________","answer":"reducing the carrying load 20%","chapter":"01: Design & Control Of Concrete Mixtures"},"59f9cac7-88e6-4e32-be56-42e355f043a8":{"question":"What is the maximum variation of stirrup location in a concrete floor ?","answer":"+/- 1 in","chapter":"01: Design & Control Of Concrete Mixtures"},"a6f35fc1-c1a1-44c1-bcc9-8108f5c0c60d":{"question":"What is the minimum length of lap in lapped splice for reinforcing bars?","answer":"12 in","chapter":"01: Design & Control Of Concrete Mixtures"},"4fd5c2d0-a4e6-452f-9683-a29c306aec58":{"question":"The most effective type of water stops are made from ______","answer":"pvc","chapter":"01: Design & Control Of Concrete Mixtures"},"0909c89c-fbe8-4c91-952f-e36e4ab497f4":{"question":"Control joint cuts in a slab should be to a depth of _______ the slab thickness.","answer":"1 / 4","chapter":"01: Design & Control Of Concrete Mixtures"},"79a5cf43-64bd-4883-8c36-d244c4aec331":{"question":"Within how many hours after placement should concrete joints be sawn?","answer":"4 to 12 hours","chapter":"01: Design & Control Of Concrete Mixtures"},"aecfb84f-ebae-4572-be9f-e0182eb0c949":{"question":"Welded wire fabric is located where and for what reason?","answer":"Upper part to prevent cracks","chapter":"01: Design & Control Of Concrete Mixtures"},"b4e71c83-0615-48a5-8d7c-4f0b52cca356":{"question":"In a mat slab, welded wire fabric is generally located __________","answer":"2 in below surface","chapter":"01: Design & Control Of Concrete Mixtures"},"bc7dd093-8e4f-4949-a65d-45fa17a35f91":{"question":"Most species allow job-site addition of water to concrete mix to an amount that ______","answer":"does not exceed the w/cm ratio","chapter":"01: Design & Control Of Concrete Mixtures"},"96bfb66d-9f98-49a4-93ce-06412dc39da5":{"question":"To pump through a 5\" line, a mix-design should consist of a well-graded mix of ______","answer":"4 in slump w/ air and some fly ash","chapter":"01: Design & Control Of Concrete Mixtures"},"c0410591-b22d-4aa5-8492-8be0ac03c2ec":{"question":"If lightweight aggregate to be pumped is not presoaked so that it <<insistently~contains 70 - 80 % of total absorption, the aggregate may ________","answer":"make pumping more difficult","chapter":"01: Design & Control Of Concrete Mixtures"},"0aaa1fae-5c8c-4777-a2bd-e23b1387124f":{"question":"Air entrapment increases the probability of which type of concrete field problems?","answer":"blistering","chapter":"01: Design & Control Of Concrete Mixtures"},"0e36ec20-7f71-407d-b488-d55d19450463":{"question":"What is the maximum weight of steel joist bridging that can be hoisted?","answer":"1000 lbs","chapter":"02: OSHA"},"5b5029f5-7c7d-41a0-814b-753b2c61a514":{"question":"When 6' or greater excavations are blocked from view by buildings or plant growth ______ is required.","answer":"a fall protection plan","chapter":"02: OSHA"},"28124ddc-4b36-4de4-8397-eecf83e9000c":{"question":"How many gallons of flammable liquid in an approved non--approved room or storage area?","answer":"25","chapter":"02: OSHA"},"64237e16-bbbd-49e1-bfc0-509603d3abd1":{"question":"A hoist tower located inside a steel structure shall be _____","answer":"enclosed on all 4 sides throughout the full height","chapter":"02: OSHA"},"53b7cb3e-4f48-4a26-aa8f-dac682863a5d":{"question":"How often should atmospheric testing be done in and around a 5' excavation trench in a confined space?","answer":"before employees enter","chapter":"02: OSHA"},"87ca0784-0f5a-4650-94f5-d6b7bcf3aff5":{"question":"Which of the following equipment is for the purpose of fall protection?","answer":"guardrail system","chapter":"02: OSHA"},"2d5c2b1c-a684-4a23-947b-e8b0d37a0cc4":{"question":"What soil classification rating is given to sand?","answer":"Type C","chapter":"02: OSHA"},"4ccbcf8d-fb2e-403b-85be-3fd6e26119c1":{"question":"What tool requires guards both above and below?","answer":"power driven circular saws","chapter":"02: OSHA"},"78458395-eb55-4273-9523-456774a64148":{"question":"Lumber piles shall not exceed 20 feet in height, provided that lumber to be handled manually is not stacked more than ___ ft high","answer":"16","chapter":"02: OSHA"},"c0d87f77-af7f-4e2e-ae0b-3e04998297f3":{"question":"An employer is responsible for all of the following safety and training education except _____","answer":"cpr","chapter":"02: OSHA"},"ee5855e2-3462-4fd1-903c-b6633b0122c6":{"question":"When dirt is moved from its natural state, this is called _____ or loose condition.","answer":"swells","chapter":"03: Pipe and Excavation"},"98a083bc-93c7-42e4-a4a1-77c9558312b3":{"question":"The bucket's maximum capacity when the material is heaped above the edges of the bucket is ______.","answer":"heaped","chapter":"03: Pipe and Excavation"},"49b59621-e160-4bb5-97d0-460a37d22992":{"question":"The contents of the bucket when it is filled to the level of the rim, no material is heaped over the rim is ________.","answer":"struck","chapter":"03: Pipe and Excavation"},"fa5bb0e4-bfc6-4554-b65b-82b577131874":{"question":"How is a load factor calculated?","answer":"Bank volume / (bank volume + swell percentage)","chapter":"03: Pipe and Excavation"},"c78eb904-46a0-4526-8ad2-03ce22ba09d4":{"question":"What type of dozer is used for fine grading, trench backfill, landscaping, light logging, and swamp dozing?","answer":"light utility bulldozer","chapter":"03: Pipe and Excavation"},"a23779b2-263f-46aa-9400-ccc6bc290baa":{"question":"If the operator fails to lift, tilt, and angle the blade just right, _______.","answer":"most of the load is lost","chapter":"03: Pipe and Excavation"},"7f0588d9-2e95-4afe-be6e-26b576930477":{"question":"Align the direction of the dozer travel with the ____ whenever possible.","answer":"blade dump area","chapter":"03: Pipe and Excavation"},"e325ef16-b37f-415e-b206-0220f4e56b82":{"question":"______ dozing increases the dozer's blade capacity and adds to the pushing force.","answer":"downgrade dozing","chapter":"03: Pipe and Excavation"},"9c3d073d-2183-4a66-bd35-758d50507ca1":{"question":"You can reduce the amount of lost load by ______. This keeps the load from slipping away.","answer":"slot dozing","chapter":"03: Pipe and Excavation"},"bf051e26-e37a-4b53-b573-ff628919d236":{"question":"What is the advantage of a U-blade vs a Semi-U blade?","answer":"It holds more material","chapter":"03: Pipe and Excavation"},"10240e40-85d5-40f0-866d-f1c997d02eb7":{"question":"What is the hardest part of graders work?","answer":"finish grading","chapter":"03: Pipe and Excavation"},"f57e33cc-0512-47a6-9465-c4ac05de2dfc":{"question":"Any self-loading scraper will be more productive in muddy soil, when assisted by a _____","answer":"dozer pushing on the blocks at the rear of the bowl","chapter":"03: Pipe and Excavation"},"62c7880a-7ce1-4ef8-aff0-910f44793c82":{"question":"The larger the pipe diameter, the smaller the fall requirement is needed to maintain a water velocity great enough to prevent ________.","answer":"solids from settling in","chapter":"03: Pipe and Excavation"},"e43d6377-b96a-4a8e-bd37-e7512285e57e":{"question":"A ______ is a small stake driven into the ground to identify a particular reference point.","answer":"hub","chapter":"03: Pipe and Excavation"},"43a040aa-558e-44cc-af1d-87853c00e21a":{"question":"If a reference stake is 20.2' from the hub and fill is to be started at a distance of 12.4' from the hub, how are these distances measured?","answer":"horizontally","chapter":"03: Pipe and Excavation"},"23494e6c-2a41-4291-ac8a-59f809e98775":{"question":"What percent slope rises at a 45 degree angle?","answer":"100%","chapter":"03: Pipe and Excavation"},"5a1a2ed3-e82c-457e-b5da-543a721572a6":{"question":"Excavate _____ trenches around the tree, deep enough to cut through the root system of the tree.","answer":"4","chapter":"03: Pipe and Excavation"},"0bcfec27-0b48-4ce1-8c2c-139ebb6400be":{"question":"What is the purpose of a trench box?","answer":"to support a wall of soil","chapter":"03: Pipe and Excavation"},"f0fb1b1f-1859-4c63-8dfd-52000082d711":{"question":"The trench box must be centered over the pipe. To maintain safety the maximum height above the pipe to install the trench box is _______.","answer":"2.5 ft","chapter":"03: Pipe and Excavation"},"f1a819d4-bc2c-432a-82c7-ce12c1e5bf88":{"question":"What is the purpose if the trench box?","answer":"To support a wall of soil","chapter":"03: Pipe and Excavation"},"8faa81e8-fc3f-4d99-84a6-9131db2aedcc":{"question":"______ is the best piece of equipment for working in mud or soft ground.","answer":"Tracked backhoe","chapter":"03: Pipe and Excavation"},"09af7d24-85e7-4b61-8b76-3b5cf6192eb4":{"question":"Which of the following methods for testing soil density does not require drilling ______.","answer":"nuclear density","chapter":"03: Pipe and Excavation"},"c832e3ab-02ce-450b-a151-87e1d6048df4":{"question":"The easiest soil compaction method is ______.","answer":"puddling","chapter":"03: Pipe and Excavation"},"829272ed-62a5-40c2-a6aa-a09def806957":{"question":"Limited working room in excavations means _______.","answer":"you can't easily use the water necessary for wetting","chapter":"03: Pipe and Excavation"},"9cf45045-7e6c-46a9-bf52-4617d2be302e":{"question":"What piece of equipment is a good choice if you have a wide trench with no crosslines?","answer":"sheepsfoot roller","chapter":"03: Pipe and Excavation"},"c69c27ee-50ce-46b9-be5c-d98e3dc23074":{"question":"To estimate earthwork you need to _______.","answer":"divide the area in sections","chapter":"03: Pipe and Excavation"},"58e44643-d73f-4954-8bbb-fe0069fed8f3":{"question":"The curving broken lines on a grading plan are ______ lines.","answer":"contour","chapter":"03: Pipe and Excavation"},"5f24cef1-9356-4340-b099-621641589b2c":{"question":"Widely spaced differing contour lines indicate _____ on a grading plan.","answer":"relatively flat area","chapter":"03: Pipe and Excavation"},"5fda9ebf-01d3-4336-a9da-09766be581b5":{"question":"______ is the easiest type of rock to rip.","answer":"Sedimentary","chapter":"03: Pipe and Excavation"},"9345d960-ef8f-416a-96da-97af87da7a20":{"question":"The level of the underground water is known as the _______.","answer":"water table","chapter":"03: Pipe and Excavation"},"8797f14e-6e70-4a39-aef7-90058e24e50d":{"question":"Wellpoint's work well in ______ soils.","answer":"sandy","chapter":"03: Pipe and Excavation"},"5ee6a2f5-1533-4176-9c0b-ad06e4d68727":{"question":"Mason's _____ is the most used tool by a mason.","answer":"trowel","chapter":"04: Masonry"},"98a5047c-8208-413d-a6e8-a1697e0c6b6c":{"question":"What is used to finish the surface of mortar joints?","answer":"jointers","chapter":"04: Masonry"},"833ddada-cf53-47dd-be80-03f749737f47":{"question":"Sled runner or joint runner - __________","answer":"produces long horizontal joints","chapter":"04: Masonry"},"c3ddd0b3-2166-4923-92ac-d5423c94e6fb":{"question":"Brick tongs are used for what purpose?","answer":"To carry bricks","chapter":"04: Masonry"},"d1b19872-e8b4-447c-b980-93c584585766":{"question":"What type of brick has the following characteristics: Brick that is highly resistant to frost action. Used where bricks are exposed to freezing weather?\n\n","answer":"grade sw","chapter":"04: Masonry"},"fb07a251-9f29-464f-9c4d-8fa4b557ec98":{"question":"These bricks are manufactured and selected to produce architectural effects resulting from non-uniformity in size, color, and texture:\n Type _______.","answer":"FBA","chapter":"04: Masonry"},"78d34476-8237-4544-840c-3a94a36a76ab":{"question":"What type of brick is identical to facing bricks but have a larger core area?","answer":"hollow bricks","chapter":"04: Masonry"},"86ae2d5f-d14f-420d-a261-fdca2d9cf18b":{"question":"A modular brick is based on a measurement of ______ inches.","answer":"4","chapter":"04: Masonry"},"cdbedda2-9ab8-4195-88b5-4b11b395b56a":{"question":"Modular bricks sizes became popular because they provided a quick and simple way of estimating the number of bricks needed. Standard modular brick is _______.","answer":"4\" X 2-2/3\" X 8\"","chapter":"04: Masonry"},"e632cacc-0978-4e7b-906a-b75a58d0d744":{"question":"_____ is a white powder or salt-like deposit on masonry walls, which is caused by water-soluble salts.","answer":"Efflorescence","chapter":"04: Masonry"},"c1271973-67fd-4e6d-8da0-0b5af771df51":{"question":"Method by which individual units are interlocked or tied together to form a wall is a _____ bond.","answer":"pattern","chapter":"04: Masonry"},"a270aca8-dd7e-4f39-8c00-8f99032e1a82":{"question":"In a stack bond, all joints line up _______.","answer":"vertically","chapter":"04: Masonry"},"38f13983-2b37-4a46-856b-aef065a1390e":{"question":"Effective in resisting rain penetration, ____ joints are recommended where heavy rains and high winds are likely to occur.","answer":"concave","chapter":"04: Masonry"},"0fa2467b-9acd-4de9-83f0-5bda90b0ee19":{"question":"What type of joint is not recommended for areas with heavy rains, high winds, and freezing temperatures?","answer":"Raked","chapter":"04: Masonry"},"113280ee-ab8f-42b1-850e-5a7616372950":{"question":"A nominal 8' X 8' X 16\" block is actually ______","answer":"7-5/8\" X 7-5/8\" X 15-5/8\"","chapter":"04: Masonry"},"115085ce-9517-4daa-9191-027dd00c293c":{"question":"Intended size of a mortar joint for a CMU is ____ inch.","answer":"3/8","chapter":"04: Masonry"},"255dc0e6-0d7c-4306-9923-9b61aacceeb3":{"question":"Which one of the following CMU's has more space for conduit or other utilities?","answer":"Two-core block","chapter":"04: Masonry"},"4656ae1a-3980-4a28-bce7-ce507496b88e":{"question":"Basic mortar ingredients include ________.","answer":"portland cement, hydrated lime, and sand","chapter":"04: Masonry"},"145ed579-1231-439e-9a3a-030bf60322db":{"question":"What is the primary aggregate in masonry mortar?","answer":"sand","chapter":"04: Masonry"},"1f15e16e-1429-4440-ac15-6c4c292cfe97":{"question":"Mortar is mostly comprised of _________.","answer":"portland cement","chapter":"04: Masonry"},"2e82e416-ff75-4fec-8aea-83f6dc604788":{"question":"Only Type ____ is recommended for masonry mortar because unhydrated oxides and plasticity are controlled.","answer":"S","chapter":"04: Masonry"},"7d374f70-2298-4c2f-9785-e3aa1a9c94bf":{"question":"Good for unreinforced masonry below grade and in contact with earth, use type ____ mortar.","answer":"M","chapter":"04: Masonry"},"6702bf8d-06fc-4666-b28b-6fd69ab9f0ff":{"question":"Type ___ mortar is a low strength mortar; suitable for general interior use in nonload bearing masonry.","answer":"N","chapter":"04: Masonry"},"6efc9979-eb45-48e9-9f9f-8fb3f2a84396":{"question":"_____ is a primary element in reinforced brick and masonry construction.","answer":"grout","chapter":"04: Masonry"},"07953bfa-c097-4b6f-8b8c-6849f1ef8cad":{"question":"For cavity walls where wind velocities will exceed 80 mph, use Type ____ mortar.","answer":"S","chapter":"04: Masonry"},"c36659df-98cd-4ed1-8e3b-93d89050e098":{"question":"What type of tie is galvanized steel and the dovetail fits into a slot formed in the beam or column?","answer":"Corrugated","chapter":"04: Masonry"},"029b05da-850f-4bdf-8986-7b73625b7b6f":{"question":"______ are used to attach roof plates, sills, etc, to masonry work.","answer":"Anchor bolts","chapter":"04: Masonry"},"55eebbef-3d90-44bf-907b-3ac119c778a9":{"question":"Masonry walls that intersect may be connected by what mean?","answer":"Strap Anchor","chapter":"04: Masonry"},"e3b936f5-0496-4e06-97a3-a0e7320420cb":{"question":"Concrete anchors are intended for installation ______.","answer":"after concrete has hardened","chapter":"04: Masonry"},"ded8f884-34a6-4a41-8cd7-7f4aebd876d5":{"question":"Mortar on the board should be kept well tempered (________________) until it is used","answer":"sprinkled lightly with water","chapter":"04: Masonry"},"0d5460c1-4939-42e4-8a9f-c342e65de339":{"question":"Produces a rough cut but is acceptable for applications where cut will be hidden is a _______ hammer.","answer":"brick","chapter":"04: Masonry"},"bbfb60ae-ce93-45e4-8411-e59250f51ba0":{"question":"Leads are usually built first ______ to establish proper height and provide a place to attach the mason's line.","answer":"at each corner","chapter":"04: Masonry"},"5223028d-dc80-4345-8535-f09ed40b433c":{"question":"A solution of ________ is used extensively as a cleaning agent for new masonry.","answer":"hydrochloric acid","chapter":"04: Masonry"},"cdb97e45-9878-454c-98b4-182d1ae9687a":{"question":"Costs about the same as acid. Use a very low pressure and a 1/4\" sandblast nozzle with a white urn sand with with _______.","answer":"60 - 120 psi","chapter":"04: Masonry"},"76d28322-ae7e-4890-8ba5-bf81f67805b2":{"question":"Cavity Masonry Walls consist of ____","answer":"a two-wythe wall that allows each wythe to react independently to stress; Usually consists of two walls separated by a continuous airspace that is 2\" or more wide.","chapter":"04: Masonry"},"221b5545-09c3-42cd-9a79-cd5a2aa3b45c":{"question":"Using a 1/4: 1 scale , 3 1/2\" will represent _________ \"","answer":"13","chapter":"05: Carpentry"},"cdaf672a-1274-496f-8b5d-87c0eb1f2e28":{"question":"Lines that terminate with arrows are ________.","answer":"dimension lines","chapter":"05: Carpentry"},"3f441352-ff4c-4cb5-ba4c-38cf66c83f6f":{"question":"What shows building with boundaries?","answer":"Plot or Site Plan","chapter":"05: Carpentry"},"5e746b21-ad8e-4506-820c-ad0503127c5e":{"question":"What shows the external views of the structure?","answer":"Elevation","chapter":"05: Carpentry"},"e0cd7cc3-a702-4c92-8ff8-200489524469":{"question":"What designates brand and model number of window?","answer":"Window schedule","chapter":"05: Carpentry"},"fd45bd10-d172-40e8-a78f-c80a21eb7e01":{"question":"Concrete is made of what 4 parts?","answer":"cement, coarse aggregate, fine aggregate, and water","chapter":"05: Carpentry"},"da15e892-56c7-46c5-b9ef-28858029462d":{"question":"_______ measures horizontal angles only.","answer":"Builder's or dumping level","chapter":"05: Carpentry"},"779b7564-0a93-4ce1-a5de-7246446eaf07":{"question":"________ is the starting point for laying out a building.","answer":"benchmark","chapter":"05: Carpentry"},"8f2a4a5e-70b6-4897-baee-30dbc08db45b":{"question":"If layout for a rectangular building is square, ___________.","answer":"the diagonals are equal.","chapter":"05: Carpentry"},"40da777d-b838-4618-a1c6-fdf7c3254939":{"question":"Install batter boards after __________.","answer":"the grades and corners have been established","chapter":"05: Carpentry"},"3385bca9-2f19-4d3d-99e5-bf83040e9392":{"question":"Minimum placement of batterboards from the point of excavation is ___________'.","answer":"4","chapter":"05: Carpentry"},"83f43130-d1ee-4135-9665-b4c30db74ad9":{"question":"__________ is represented by the top of the batter boards.","answer":"Foundation height","chapter":"05: Carpentry"},"e58fab36-cd0f-4838-8d0e-1b42b07d348b":{"question":"Sides of footings are molded by boards referred to as ___________.","answer":"haunch boards","chapter":"05: Carpentry"},"e3b58dc4-a474-4617-a722-40ed67b9d849":{"question":"________ are used to hold foundation wall forms together.","answer":"Snap ties","chapter":"05: Carpentry"},"3e5d2313-251e-4bb0-9b9b-34196606713f":{"question":"______ are used over window and door openings in concrete block wall.","answer":"Lintels","chapter":"05: Carpentry"},"6be5d246-9701-4de7-b76d-966b2a099acd":{"question":"When lumber dries it tends to shrink _________.","answer":"more in width than length","chapter":"05: Carpentry"},"d724a383-3ba8-4955-8dea-5112550229e1":{"question":"When a piece of lumber is cut along the natural age ring, it is called _________.","answer":"shake","chapter":"05: Carpentry"},"9dcfcbf4-676f-462c-8806-76dd82949633":{"question":"Place crown on _________ of glulam beams.","answer":"up or on top","chapter":"05: Carpentry"},"a65c0d8e-668d-423a-af5d-70dba0d975d7":{"question":"Subfloor plywood underlayment spacing is __________.","answer":"1/8\" on all sides","chapter":"05: Carpentry"},"3175c9fe-32a3-49e6-b03c-c79fc5559c87":{"question":"Support under a wood deck is ____________.","answer":"a girder","chapter":"05: Carpentry"},"b119e4a3-fb6f-4e6f-b4d6-188c41c2e335":{"question":"Correct order for hanging a bi-fold door is ________.","answer":"Top track first, then fasten the lower track to the floor directly under the top track","chapter":"05: Carpentry"},"fc27ea92-da5b-484e-ac74-1a82443183b2":{"question":"1/4\", lightweight, low-cost, utility gypsum panel is NOT recommended for _________.","answer":"metal studs","chapter":"06: Gypsum handbook"},"0ae7f8d4-0267-46a9-88de-e22f027ba215":{"question":"What type of screw is used for aluminum trim to steel framing?","answer":"Type S bugle head","chapter":"06: Gypsum handbook"},"db48e9c9-f105-43ed-9a36-f27ec4b430b8":{"question":"What type of screw is used for steel to poured concrete block?","answer":"a tapcon anchor","chapter":"06: Gypsum handbook"},"e77c4e08-8fe6-4db1-8ef1-7970cfee49f6":{"question":"Space metal furring channels 24\" on center ________ or other structural members.","answer":"at right angles to bar joists","chapter":"06: Gypsum handbook"},"199c38c6-13ff-4dbe-911d-3e3766040cef":{"question":"Saddle-tie furring channels to bar joists with triple-strand ________ at each intersection.","answer":"18 gauge","chapter":"06: Gypsum handbook"},"b1005a00-7e0e-44a0-9b77-06835901cdd5":{"question":"Gypsum boards should be placed inside under cover and _____.","answer":"stacked flat on a clean floor in the center of the largest room","chapter":"06: Gypsum handbook"},"a8ed309f-30cd-4e0a-9804-cdfe8ff37164":{"question":"Apply gypsum boards so that the ends and edges occur over framing members, except _______.","answer":"when joints are at right angles to the framing members","chapter":"06: Gypsum handbook"},"a194cfb7-390a-4308-a3b6-13b224908b4a":{"question":"Arrange drywall joints on opposite sides of partition ________.","answer":"so they occur on different studs","chapter":"06: Gypsum handbook"},"7010a570-c911-42e2-8fca-e6cdde7e2b18":{"question":"Apply gypsum boards ___________.","answer":"first to the ceiling and then the walls","chapter":"06: Gypsum handbook"},"72d617d4-e92d-494a-8c1d-5188061388a3":{"question":"On sidewalls space screws _______ for gypsum panels.","answer":"16\" on center maximum","chapter":"06: Gypsum handbook"},"7c5c21b9-d8d5-42b0-9496-7ed69fca67a5":{"question":"What type of roof looks like a barn?","answer":"gambrel","chapter":"07: Roofing"},"70d28e16-7b18-4b17-92aa-5511317fe0f8":{"question":"What is the gable height of a building that is 36' wide with a slope of 6:12?","answer":"9'","chapter":"07: Roofing"},"6458ce0e-e0d5-4ab1-be85-d73ac13ec2b3":{"question":"A building with a hip roof that is 57' X 39' with a 1' over hang will have a ridge board length of ______.","answer":"18'","chapter":"07: Roofing"},"2b3b186d-f2c8-4dce-b72c-c28ede4f5ff6":{"question":"A rectangular structure measures 36' X 24'. It has a hip roof with an overhang of 2' around the perimeter. How many 10' lengths of 1 x 8 fascia boards are require? allow 5% for waste.","answer":"136 LF","chapter":"07: Roofing"},"5f14f430-deb0-487a-8c7b-362900a1265b":{"question":"Solid roof sheathing is recommended for shakes and wood shingles where ______.","answer":"the outside temperature is 0 degrees Fahrenheit or colder or the january mean temperature is 25 degrees or less","chapter":"07: Roofing"},"6a56b890-80b1-4b29-9e46-8a3b6dda3060":{"question":"Boards be used for solid roof sheathing should not be wider than a _______.","answer":"1 X 6","chapter":"07: Roofing"},"e12cc713-f5fe-4fc4-884d-e68b69471545":{"question":"At an eave end, the drip edge is installed ______.","answer":"under the felt at the eaves","chapter":"07: Roofing"},"477b7c2a-b156-45a8-9cec-900a4972d771":{"question":"Spacing of wood shingles on spaced board sheathing (non-continuous sheathing) should be __________.","answer":"1 X 4s spaced on center equal to the weather exposure","chapter":"07: Roofing"},"4215166e-5060-4f5d-ae85-82526cda335c":{"question":"The process of water leaking into the walls and ceiling areas from a result of freeze thaw cycles of snow is called _______.","answer":"freezeback (ice dam)","chapter":"07: Roofing"},"08ef3da0-52fb-42f6-8f33-9626c7c3862d":{"question":"flashing should be installed ____ inches beyond the interior face of the exterior wall line for slopes less than 4:12.","answer":"24","chapter":"07: Roofing"},"5d776a72-2edc-4259-a8cb-9860afbf2d8a":{"question":"Adding valley flashing to the roof will help with ________.","answer":"weather protection","chapter":"07: Roofing"},"a1ed6d24-9609-48bd-bc5e-d12af4cf22a7":{"question":"Galvanized steel and aluminum valley flashing are made of at least _____ metal.","answer":"26 or 29 gauge","chapter":"07: Roofing"},"4cf51095-5dc3-4f37-8b34-d4976e11bbee":{"question":"What agency determines the fire rating for asphalt shingles?","answer":"the UL","chapter":"07: Roofing"},"8730e425-456f-439e-ae86-03841cd0ffeb":{"question":"Open valley's are not recommended for _____, because they are more likely to leak.","answer":"3-tab ashpalt shingles","chapter":"07: Roofing"},"af27ae0d-6ed4-44fa-982a-2f3a64a318be":{"question":"What type of valley has a faster installation and looks more professional?","answer":"closed cut","chapter":"07: Roofing"},"c33f02c6-c8c8-40c0-a0aa-3c4e8bb84cdc":{"question":"What type of valley is fully laced and should be applied alternately to both sides of the valley?","answer":"woven","chapter":"07: Roofing"},"01c892d8-9d08-4945-abe6-7926312e2049":{"question":"What is the nail length for strip shingles on a new deck?","answer":"1 1/4\"","chapter":"07: Roofing"},"01c1ae66-f4ea-4b96-981c-33c8dd32e0b4":{"question":"Approximately how many pounds of nails are required per square of asphalt shingles?","answer":"2 1/2 lbs","chapter":"07: Roofing"},"ec5e5d65-1298-4111-a80e-aca3df5b9dc2":{"question":"One square is equal to 100 SF & there are _____ shingles per square.","answer":"80","chapter":"07: Roofing"},"3d804b21-59e5-4dd3-bf78-881902768f4a":{"question":"A roof measuring 100' X 100' will have how many roofing squares?","answer":"100","chapter":"07: Roofing"},"f87579b7-bce4-4494-aaba-ffd2985cf563":{"question":"What is the best material to use as a solid roof decking?","answer":"plywood","chapter":"07: Roofing"},"57936a9d-156f-4f04-9f2d-29822f4acebe":{"question":"Flash valleys with a _______ before you install the main roof.","answer":"36\" wide strip","chapter":"07: Roofing"},"273a303c-ef2d-49cc-aef8-acde588aca8c":{"question":"Blue label cedar shingles have _____ bundles per square.","answer":"4","chapter":"07: Roofing"},"39506cae-dc12-4bd7-92fe-8ab3e8b289b7":{"question":"Concrete tiles should be installed with a _____ top lap.","answer":"3\"","chapter":"07: Roofing"},"5dc3b487-fb29-4269-b52b-89528eec9cf6":{"question":"______ pounds of asphalt bitumen is required per square between felts with an application tolerance of plus or minus 15%.","answer":"25","chapter":"07: Roofing"},"aa34881b-06a1-424e-bda9-fe0290e408ee":{"question":"Steep asphalt is the most commonly used. It ranges from dead-level to 1/2:12 slope. Steep asphalt softens at 180 to 205 degrees Fahrenheit. You can safely heat Steep asphalt to 450 to 475 degrees Fahrenheit. This is Type ____.","answer":"3","chapter":"07: Roofing"},"949f627e-2c22-4b3d-8621-4c63c0917b2e":{"question":"The flash point on all Types of Asphalt is between ___ to ___ degrees.","answer":"437 - 500","chapter":"07: Roofing"},"b7419061-aae2-4eca-a30e-eb2c754fde9c":{"question":"A properly installed BUR will last ____ years.","answer":"20","chapter":"07: Roofing"},"a1767530-be3a-47aa-b963-ee00e5d9ca00":{"question":"How do you identify a roof leak?","answer":"Look for shingles that are worn, curled or damaged.","chapter":"07: Roofing"},"661f4815-231b-4128-af34-8d1287a6fef6":{"question":"Typically, the cause of leaks around flashing are due to ______.","answer":"improper shingling around the flashing","chapter":"07: Roofing"},"8fd415a2-d2da-4294-80dd-b19f644e3a07":{"question":"What is the correct way to repair an asphalt shingle?","answer":"Apply roofing cement and sprinkling on loose granules, then rub them into the cement","chapter":"07: Roofing"},"11918b5b-269c-441f-852e-d5f50c3c3aa7":{"question":"The most common leak on a wood shingle roof occurs _________.","answer":"where joints or splits line up in 3 adjacent courses","chapter":"07: Roofing"},"babbf385-4c6c-4d92-9888-9f97de15d4ea":{"question":"What is the correct procedure for replacing broken slate?","answer":"Insert the new piece of slate underneath the 2 overlying courses and nail it into place","chapter":"07: Roofing"},"849a2d33-7f4b-4ae4-ab64-6ed90259f2f1":{"question":"A roof is considered beyond repair when the ______.","answer":"repairs costs exceed 80% of the replacement costs","chapter":"07: Roofing"},"d70171d4-eaad-4633-a244-e3254ee4cd95":{"question":"Hip roof ventilation should include ______.","answer":"inlet openings in soffit area of the eaves","chapter":"07: Roofing"},"7ff2b76e-d733-4cbd-86d5-d37ff146d74a":{"question":"Depths for open web steel joists range from 8\" to a maximum of ____ inches.","answer":"30","chapter":"08: Steel Joist"},"0e113191-cf48-4458-a23c-8a61140b5e28":{"question":"Spans range from 8' to 60'. Standard bearing depth is _____.","answer":"2-1/2\" for open web steel joists","chapter":"08: Steel Joist"},"af983cc7-2189-4410-ae4a-d791fa86d45f":{"question":"Joist designation of 18K7 the denotes the ____.","answer":"chord selection","chapter":"08: Steel Joist"},"80ea0cf6-caef-41bd-b54c-3405baf204c6":{"question":"Standard bearing depth is ____ inches for longspan joists.","answer":"5","chapter":"08: Steel Joist"},"b3a25481-3520-4bae-83b2-87b7e73b6970":{"question":"Bearing depths are _____ inches for underslung joist girders.","answer":"7 1/2","chapter":"08: Steel Joist"},"c902542f-9983-40f0-8252-d6449240e7c7":{"question":"Lengths run from 20' to 120' and top chords can be either ______.","answer":"single pitched of doubled pitched","chapter":"08: Steel Joist"},"910b798f-133d-49ee-9007-8e6eee0ce097":{"question":"A joist girder designation of 36G9N6K means what?","answer":"36 = nominal girder depth at the mid-span; G = indicates that it is a joist girder; 9N = indicates that there are 9 joist spacings","chapter":"08: Steel Joist"},"f7222c19-42ed-4cbf-a7c0-adb31fe6a9ec":{"question":"Joist products are typically unloaded by crane or forklift. Whenever possible, joists products should be ______.","answer":"unloaded by bundles","chapter":"08: Steel Joist"},"e902a357-5348-48d2-ba5c-03866b3c729b":{"question":"Bundles should NEVER be lifted ______.","answer":"by their strapping","chapter":"08: Steel Joist"},"d84d4854-adee-4bfd-aa13-3e2162bf6522":{"question":"Standard bridging bundle weight: The maximum weight of these bundles is _____ pounds.","answer":"1000","chapter":"08: Steel Joist"},"36a9cf91-07d8-4a2e-849b-5dbe67b19b63":{"question":"Joists should be stored in the same position in which they are shipped, joists that are shipped _____.","answer":"vertically should be stored vertically","chapter":"08: Steel Joist"},"b149e737-48bf-4893-a280-24e65eb72b04":{"question":"Joist girders are primary structural members that are normally supported by ______.","answer":"columns","chapter":"08: Steel Joist"},"9a1b3d4b-8127-4c36-91d4-0df19663e7dc":{"question":"The top chord of a joist girder can be either parallel with the bottom chord; single pitched, or double pitched. In many instances joist girders are not loaded symmetrically consequently, it is imperative that the \"TAG END\" of a joist girder be placed as _______.","answer":"indicated on the  joist placement plan","chapter":"08: Steel Joist"},"82ca46ec-98ef-4707-8899-e8364f157ff5":{"question":"Joist girders must be erected singly. They are to be properly hoisted with attachments ______.","answer":"placed at top chord panel points","chapter":"08: Steel Joist"},"d4d9f65f-29c5-4a0e-8461-ff2b21f1ef96":{"question":"If the ends of the joist girders are bolted, the bolts should be _____.","answer":"inserted immediately after the girders are set","chapter":"08: Steel Joist"},"fba9162f-2c74-456a-83d5-03d9a6eaa9f6":{"question":"Joist girders must bear a minimum of ___ inches on steel supports.","answer":"4","chapter":"08: Steel Joist"},"12bb9ce6-b8d1-452c-8449-3a03a85b4f36":{"question":"Joist girders must bear a minimum of ___ inches on steel plates supported by masonry or concrete.\n","answer":"6","chapter":"08: Steel Joist"},"68773895-d217-41a5-8993-14af962d2374":{"question":"Since joist girders are NOT bridged as are joists, some bracing is normally _____.","answer":"required for the bottom chord","chapter":"08: Steel Joist"},"c1ca6b07-a0e8-401f-a895-ae42c678c241":{"question":"When a joist girder is removed from a bundle, ______.","answer":"hook the cable at the midpoint of the bottom to remove it from the bundle","chapter":"08: Steel Joist"},"824c833e-7766-4181-a0c1-6a3111aea119":{"question":"Immediately after each subsequent joist is set in its proper position, both sides of the joist bearing _______.","answer":"seat at one end of the joist must be welded","chapter":"08: Steel Joist"},"74cb4396-27b4-402d-92d8-d73cca7dc0e6":{"question":"Under no circumstances are construction loads of any description to be placed ______!","answer":"on unbridged joists","chapter":"08: Steel Joist"},"3892f7cb-1058-4ef8-a75c-c4d949f9dc6c":{"question":"For spans up through 60', welded horizontal bridging may be used except where the row of ____________.","answer":"bridging nearest the mid-span is required to be bolted diagonal bridging","chapter":"08: Steel Joist"},"ff922d7a-dc59-4d62-a506-ef93b305cec2":{"question":"Hoist cables shall not be released on a 33' to 60' longspan joist until there is __________.","answer":"one row of bolted diagonal bridging nearest the mid-span","chapter":"08: Steel Joist"},"edb58894-f534-48a0-a880-266e357283e0":{"question":"It is the erector's responsibility to ensure that the joist is straight lengthwise, and vertically plumb. As bridging is installed, _____ in the joist should be removed & vertical misalignment should be corrected.","answer":"sweep","chapter":"08: Steel Joist"},"a262bb72-e28f-42fa-b048-8816639ddd9a":{"question":"At no time are more than ____ employees allowed on long span joists greater than 100', but less than or equal to 144 feet until all bridging is installed and anchored.","answer":"2","chapter":"08: Steel Joist"},"87197f56-1d4a-4d6b-b0bc-7110ac87d066":{"question":"The vast majority of bridging is welded, horizontal type. This bridging is typically furnished as _____.","answer":"angle shape in standard 20' lengths","chapter":"08: Steel Joist"},"dded38a4-ef81-4550-a59d-3cdda51f643d":{"question":"In erecting bottom bearing (square ended) joists, it is IMPERATIVE that they be _________.","answer":"erected right side up","chapter":"08: Steel Joist"},"f64fd7ce-94fd-4f28-b6c3-1451e2575bd5":{"question":"When _______ are a design consideration, a row of bottom chord bridging is required near each end of the joists.","answer":"uplift forces","chapter":"08: Steel Joist"},"0e2bd6f5-4c76-410a-a3ab-37d9d75b5749":{"question":"Horizontal bridging shall be used in the space adjacent to the wall to allow for proper deflection of the joist nearest the wall. This shall be lapped a minimum of ____ inches.","answer":"2","chapter":"08: Steel Joist"},"761fe5eb-170d-48b3-9ea7-25a98c508e23":{"question":"______ is defined as an arching or curvature.","answer":"Camber","chapter":"08: Steel Joist"},"f3029fd9-ae82-4ea4-b1f6-2ffe835784bb":{"question":"What is the approximate camber in a 50' longspan joist?","answer":"1\"","chapter":"08: Steel Joist"},"71ddff0d-9be2-4564-8890-ab3dd3c9dd39":{"question":"Report any damage to joist ________.","answer":"jobsite supervisor or supplier","chapter":"08: Steel Joist"},"9ddd3f53-fe95-4284-9461-580c87bb40be":{"question":"__________ the ends of all square-end joists.","answer":"Restrain and stabilize","chapter":"08: Steel Joist"},"0ff31e34-6353-4431-888e-2c30959e6f2c":{"question":"Securely ____ the ends of all rows of bridging.","answer":"anchor","chapter":"08: Steel Joist"},"e9ef5740-bfc5-4cca-9fa9-51f3b3087401":{"question":"Ensure that mates are _________ matched on spliced joists.","answer":"matched","chapter":"08: Steel Joist"},"4556b0ca-4170-4197-a000-909e0044a088":{"question":"Don't _____ to secure lower chord bridging.","answer":"use tack welds","chapter":"08: Steel Joist"},"d5ff8a6c-05b9-4b4d-b8a6-4568c93da255":{"question":"Don't repair or alter joists without the approval of _____.","answer":"registered design professional and/or joist manufacturer","chapter":"08: Steel Joist"},"814d80a4-f068-4bc6-bed4-bd1518f5c724":{"question":"The ends of K-Series joists shall extend a distance of not less than ____ inches over masonry or concrete support and be anchored to the steel bearing plate.","answer":"4","chapter":"08: Steel Joist"},"648bb851-48cb-4b38-8499-b65172b547f5":{"question":"The joist must bear a minimum of ____ \" on the steel bearing plate or steel supports.","answer":"2 1/2","chapter":"08: Steel Joist"},"b38980fb-272b-4087-8845-a9add482569c":{"question":"What is the minimum number of rows for a K-Series joist with a chord size of #6 and a span of 34' to be used in a two-story building?","answer":"3 rows","chapter":"08: Steel Joist"},"fa9cdf77-e612-4cdd-83b7-16dda9f89191":{"question":"After installation and adequate fastening, floor deck serves several purposes. What are they?","answer":"1. Acts as a working platform; 2. stabilizes frame; 3. Serves as a concrete form for the slab","chapter":"08: Steel Joist"},"95043387-d5ba-4129-b3b1-010bb1b65128":{"question":"Composite floor deck is normally installed so the ______.","answer":"panel ends do not overlap.","chapter":"08: Steel Joist"},"74c7bb82-9ef3-4b6b-aa6b-34bf7132857e":{"question":"Roof deck is not designed to act compositely with other materials. The roof deck ________.","answer":"acts alone in transferring horizontal and vertical loads into the building frame.","chapter":"08: Steel Joist"},"abdf4eb4-5d19-4a51-b016-59a8e5fe4ede":{"question":"Roof deck is typically installed to endlap approximately ___ inches over supports.","answer":"2","chapter":"08: Steel Joist"},"736ac289-1eca-426d-8e67-fcbe7f97d0f4":{"question":"______ can be used in the same manner as floor deck. Electrical, telephone and computer wires are easily run through the chase created between the the deck panel and the bottom sheet. ","answer":"Cellular deck","chapter":"08: Steel Joist"},"c97c25c0-c38e-48e3-a47e-19bd66517eaa":{"question":"A 3' x 12\" composite floor deck will have a nominal thickness range of .03\" to .06\" and a weight range of ____ to ____ per square foot.","answer":"2, 4","chapter":"08: Steel Joist"},"d37d4722-7dee-40ac-8778-efa255cadd17":{"question":"F-deck may be referred to as _____ for the name, .03\" to .06\" for the thickness & 2 to 4 PSF for the weight.","answer":"1 1/2\" x 6\"","chapter":"08: Steel Joist"},"a89e83a7-89e1-4e4e-818a-3b6287907189":{"question":"The weight range for cellular floor decking is from ____ to ____ PSF","answer":"4, 7","chapter":"08: Steel Joist"},"8f518587-e067-4cca-905c-cebc3217f8bc":{"question":"Steel deck is banded into bundles that can weigh several thousand pounds but the deck bundle weight will be limited to a maximum of _____ for deck to be applied to joists.","answer":"4000","chapter":"08: Steel Joist"},"4592bd08-ee98-4685-815c-668218792d57":{"question":"If ground storage is needed, the deck bundles should be ____.","answer":"stored off the ground, with one end elevated to provide drainage","chapter":"08: Steel Joist"},"e8b820cf-6ce0-4915-b2ae-91fe1793d368":{"question":"Deck bundles must ______ be placed on the frame near a main supporting beam at a column or wall.","answer":"always","chapter":"08: Steel Joist"},"ad16fefd-ca5d-4971-a76f-e454b2351853":{"question":"Bundles should be landed so that the _____ rather than having one or both ends cantilevered.","answer":"ends of the bundles resting a bearing surface","chapter":"08: Steel Joist"},"abbbc141-21e4-429f-80cd-adbc7ac112ec":{"question":"A working area should be at least ____ feet wide.","answer":"12","chapter":"08: Steel Joist"},"5683816e-74d6-4016-8f4c-2a09e454b450":{"question":"When aligning the edge (side) lap, the worker should _____.","answer":"kneel","chapter":"08: Steel Joist"},"adb022b1-9296-4c32-9b71-a5ed8adc42e9":{"question":"Deck fastening to the structural frame can be accomplished with _______.","answer":"welds, self-drilling screws, air driven, and powder driven","chapter":"08: Steel Joist"},"aa6dc29f-4fa7-4302-b3a4-fe49cef9faf0":{"question":"Screws are typically ________ with a special drill point when used to attach decking.","answer":"#12's or 1/4\" in diameter","chapter":"08: Steel Joist"},"ee4c4b19-33b6-43b4-a986-c5fc0fbe8756":{"question":"Weld washers are not recommended for deck thickness of ______ (minimum of 22 gauge) and greater.","answer":"0.028\" thick","chapter":"08: Steel Joist"},"95fb9dfc-393b-4570-9e82-fd97f2ba5c15":{"question":"A good weld will have _____ % or more of its perimeter working.","answer":"75","chapter":"08: Steel Joist"},"86fdb1eb-1f31-4d0e-8be4-ff9c27c05d13":{"question":"Welding side laps is not recommended for decks type _____ or lighter (0.028\" minimum).","answer":"22","chapter":"08: Steel Joist"},"b6371969-d2a0-4243-937e-bbe2fb654439":{"question":"Weld washers should _____ be used at side laps between supports.","answer":"never","chapter":"08: Steel Joist"},"bcf2e437-180a-43f7-afcf-90c53ca5c45a":{"question":"No reinforcing is generally required for an opening of 6\"as long as not more than _____ webs are removed.","answer":"2","chapter":"08: Steel Joist"},"1c66b5bc-bbf1-45bf-8b21-1ce41ef655c3":{"question":"For holes or dents greater than a rib (8\" to 13\"), it is advisable to use a _____ to cover it.","answer":"0.057\" minimum plate","chapter":"08: Steel Joist"},"a418f06a-690b-4693-a362-e0dba10d84f9":{"question":"Details for an opening up to 24\" perpendicular to deck. Should be _____.","answer":"reinforced on each side","chapter":"08: Steel Joist"},"5b355b36-0522-4e08-8d60-4cc4c2a28bd9":{"question":"Details for an opening up to 12\" perpendicular to deck. Should be reinforced to _______.","answer":"each cell all around","chapter":"08: Steel Joist"},"18bb5a76-8ddc-4be8-809d-963c1370d9e2":{"question":"The deck should have been selected to provide at least ____ pounds per square foot capacity as a working platform.","answer":"50","chapter":"08: Steel Joist"},"0ba82d30-a258-447c-8499-43363ac81940":{"question":"If the deck is to act as a diaphragm during construction, it must be realized that the diaphragm is not effective until all deck units are _____.","answer":"placed and fully connected","chapter":"08: Steel Joist"},"c71d642d-cc11-48de-a709-65ccee5ffa22":{"question":"A chimney shall extend how many feet higher than any portion of a building?\n\na. 2'\nb. 3'\nc. 5'\nd. 6'","answer":"a.","chapter":"09: Code Books","reference_1":"IRC 1003.9","reference_2":"IBC 2113.11.2.5"},"e444a20f-fa42-4567-b797-4ebb78765fcd":{"question":"What is the MINIMUM net clear opening of an exit window located at the grade floor of a single residence?\n\na. 5.0 square feet\nb. 5.7 square feet\nc. 6.0 square feet\nd. 6.7 square feet","answer":"a.","reference_1":"IRC 310.1.1","reference_2":"IBC 1026.2 Exception","chapter":"09: Code Books"},"f477e8d3-f0a4-4df8-ae4d-1c8588df8564":{"question":"What is the minimum width of a walkway on a platform scaffold?\n\na. 24\"\nb. 36\"\nc. 18\"\nd. 12\"","answer":"c.","reference_1":"OSHA","reference_2":"","chapter":"09: Code Books"},"b893addf-0617-4a7c-beb3-7fe5c8440546":{"question":"Who has the authority to render interpretations of the building code?\n\na. building officials\nb. contractor\nc. architect\nd. engineer","answer":"a.","reference_1":"IRC 104.1","reference_2":"IBC 104.1","chapter":"09: Code Books"},"5bdef667-650d-4b2a-ad61-35aed01add57":{"question":"The grade adjacent to a structure MUST be sloped away from the building to create a positive draining. The slope should not be less than _____.\n\na. 5%\nb. 6%\nc. 8%\nd. 10%","answer":"a.","reference_1":"IRC 401.3","reference_2":"IBC 1803.3","chapter":"09: Code Books"},"d1e57bf3-a88f-4cc2-9374-1714aaea20fc":{"question":"What is the minimum slope for lapped non soldered seam metal roof without lap sealant?\n\na. 2:12\nb. 3:12\nc. 4:12\nd. 5:12","answer":"b.","reference_1":"IRC 905.10.2","reference_2":"IBC 1507.4.2","chapter":"09: Code Books"},"6cdf6c9b-0f2b-41a6-8129-cb1036b748d6":{"question":"What is the MAXIMUM spacing of an interior bearing wall framed with 2 x 6's to support a roof and ceiling only?\n\na. 16 inches on center\nb. 20 inches on center\nc. 24 inches on center\nd. 28 inches on center","answer":".c","reference_1":"IRC 602.3(5)","reference_2":"IBC 2308.9.1","chapter":"09: Code Books"},"855597bf-9499-4b01-a630-ce36b621401e":{"question":"Footings shall extend how far below undisturbed soil or properly compacted fill?\n\na. 6\"\nb. 8\"\nc. 10\"\nd. 12\"","answer":"d.","reference_1":"IRC 403.1.4","reference_2":"IBC 1805.2","chapter":"09: Code Books"},"ce9acb72-9cb5-4018-b4f4-5eef559d3b04":{"question":"What is the minimum thickness of aluminum valley flashing?\n\na. .0179\nb. .024\nc. .013\nd. .0162","answer":"b.","reference_1":"IRC 905.2.8.2","reference_2":"IBC 1507.2.9.2","chapter":"09: Code Books"},"6a23b0a1-adab-4f57-8e26-f0b30f3020c0":{"question":"A 24 inch #2 taper sawn shakes of naturally durable wood roof with a 4:12 slope should have a maximum exposure of how many inches?\n\na. 5 1/2\nb. 7 1/2\nc. 10\nd. 5","answer":"b.","reference_1":"IRC 905.8.6","reference_2":"IBC 1507.9.7","chapter":"09: Code Books"},"ffa1b05c-70c3-488d-a276-b5bec2f59f2c":{"question":"What is the minimum offset of end joints in double top plates?\n\na. 12\"\nb. 24\"\nc. 28\"\nd. 48\"","answer":"b./d.","reference_1":"IRC 602.3.2","reference_2":"IBC 2300.9.2.1","chapter":"09: Code Books"},"43452fdb-cc44-46e9-bfd6-2debeef4545b":{"question":"Purlins used to support roof loads must be at least _______.\n\na. 2 x 6\nb. one size larger than the rafter it is bracing\nc. no less than one size smaller than the rafter it is bracing\nd. the size of the rafter it is supporting.","answer":"d.","reference_1":"IRC 802.5.1","reference_2":"IBC 2308.10.5","chapter":"09: Code Books"},"901ae113-f337-40d4-81c7-c52ea23c5405":{"question":"Wood siding installed on the exterior of a structure must have a clearance of ___ inches from the ground.\n\na. 4\nb. 6\nc. 8\nd. 10","answer":"d.","reference_1":"IRC 317.1#5","reference_2":"IBC 2304.11.6","chapter":"09: Code Books"},"10f482bd-b3a0-4d23-859a-7a228588197a":{"question":"Sole plate of exterior walls on monolithic slabs are anchored not more than how many feet apart?\n\na. 4'\nb. 5'\nc. 6'\nd. 8'","answer":"c.","reference_1":"IRC 403.1.6","reference_2":"IBC 2308.6","chapter":"09: Code Books"},"7925aaf3-7e18-4282-9efc-b0d9108469e0":{"question":"What is the maximum outside diameter of a circular handrail?\n\na. 1\"\nb. 2\"\nc. 2 1/2\"\nd. 4","answer":"d.","reference_1":"IRC 311.7.7.3","reference_2":"IBC 1012.3","chapter":"09: Code Books"},"93fe7d37-0fd9-4452-86ba-c003936e5d40":{"question":"1. For ramps extended for use other than specifically for means of egress, the maximum allowable slope is:\n\na. 8%\nb. 10%\nc. 10.5%\nd. 12.5%","answer":"d.","reference_1":"IRC 311.8.1","reference_2":"IBC 1010.2","chapter":"09: Code Books"},"3a88b3c1-c3f9-4986-a89e-494a5a570153":{"question":"A hole must be bored in a wood stud and needs to be placed near the edge. What is the closest the hole can be placed to the edge?\n\na. 1/2\"\nb. 3/8\"\nc. 5/8\"\nd. 7/16\"","answer":"c.","reference_1":"IRC 602.6 #2","reference_2":"IBC 2308.9.11","chapter":"09: Code Books"},"17091674-c7dc-4e76-b8a1-ab72036d3996":{"question":"Which of the following is not found on a certificate of occupancy?\n\na. if an automatic sprinkler is provided\nb. name and address of the owner\nc. name of the building official\nd. contractor's license number","answer":"d.","reference_1":"IRC 110.3","reference_2":"IBC 110.2","chapter":"09: Code Books"},"7d4a5248-84a3-4d21-9230-5db4bee99407":{"question":"Given: The floor of combustion chamber to the top of the flue is 18 feet. The fireplace opening is 2,200 square inches. What is the minimum cross-sectional area required for a rectangular chimney flue?\n\na. 125 square inches\nb. 140 square inches\nc. 168 square inches\nd. 269 square inches","answer":"c.","reference_1":"IRC 1003.15.2 Table","reference_2":"IBC 2113.16 Table","chapter":"09: Code Books"},"93605ef9-b55d-486f-a1f0-79ea39c30775":{"question":"The required joint laps for approved vapor barrier to be placed between a concrete floor slab and the grade is ___ inches.","answer":"c.","reference_1":"IRC 506.2.3","reference_2":"IBC 1911.1","chapter":"09: Code Books"},"e98f4762-727e-4246-84ad-a983eb9f70d7":{"question":"For an emergency escape opening in a habitable space, the minimum net clear opening width is specifie as ____ inches.\n\na. 20\nb. 22\nc. 24\nd. 28","answer":"a.","reference_1":"IRC 310.1.3","reference_2":"IBC 1026.2.1","chapter":"09: Code Books"},"ebd148d2-629a-4291-814d-8365ef933693":{"question":"A notch must be placed in a ceiling joist. The nominal size of the joist is 2 x 10 and spans 12 feet 8 inches. What is the maximum notch that can be placed on the top, 2 feet from the exterior wall?\n\na. 1.67 inches\nb. 1.54 inches\nc. 1.33 inches\nd. 0 inches","answer":"b.","reference_1":"IRC 802.7.1","reference_2":"IBC 2308.10.4.2","chapter":"09: Code Books"},"dcfe78b9-4866-4abf-85e5-fb854afa7334":{"question":"Exterior air intake shall not be located in any of the following areas except:\n\na. garage\nb. outside a dwelling\nc. basement\nd. attic","answer":"b.","reference_1":"IRC 1006.2","reference_2":"IBC 2111.13.3","chapter":"09: Code Books"},"d18493a2-e6e7-4992-82ec-bfbe9dd7c9de":{"question":"SPU #2 is to be installed 16\" on center in a residential living area with a dead load of 20 PSF. The length of the room is 14'6\". What size floor joist is required?\n\na. 2 x 6\nb. 2 x 8\nc. 2 x 10\nd. 2 x 12","answer":"d.","reference_1":"IRC 502.3.1(2)","reference_2":"IBC 2308.8.2","chapter":"09: Code Books"},"81f54670-47d4-4c71-b590-e944c0b586a6":{"question":"The minimum uniformly distributed live load for a room with an intended use of sleeping is designated as ____ psf.\n\na. 10\nb. 20\nc. 30\nd. 50","answer":"c.","reference_1":"IRC Table 301.5","reference_2":"IBC Table 1607.1","chapter":"09: Code Books"},"89f96c37-8bc7-4b09-bfe0-5605f9ca7bb7":{"question":"The maximum flame spread is ___ for any structure's wall and ceiling finishes. This does not apply to most trim finishes.\n\na. 75\nb. 150\nc. 200\nd. 250","answer":"c.","reference_1":"IRC 302.9.1","reference_2":"IBC 803.1","chapter":"09: Code Books"},"64c65b91-fc66-4381-ad1a-2fa8a7313a9e":{"question":"What is the maximum size hole that can be placed in any 4\" nominal stud for a load-bearing wall?\n\na. 1.4\nb. 1.6\nc. 2.0\nd. 2.2","answer":"a.","reference_1":"IRC 602.6","reference_2":"IBC 2308.9.11 (40% of 3.5\")","chapter":"09: Code Books"},"ad0a5153-ad1c-4b60-a740-0c650f5d309d":{"question":"Purlins used to support roof loads must be at least _____.\na. 2 x 6\nb. one size larger than the rafter it's bracing\nc. No less than one size smaller than the rafter it's bracing\nd. The size of the rafter it is supporting","answer":"d.","reference_1":"IRC 802.5.1","reference_2":"IBC 2308.10.5","chapter":"09: Code Books"},"3bf3e334-3fd5-4902-ae75-e5b1d9e5c411":{"question":"Masonry chimneys constructed of hollow masonry units shall be grouted solid with not less than ____ inches of nominal thickness.\n\na. 2\nb. 3\nc. 4\nd. 6","answer":"c.","reference_1":"IRC 1003.10","reference_2":"IBC 2113.10","chapter":"09: Code Books"},"d4f270c7-2269-4be4-9c4f-80a7686f9e85":{"question":"A hearth extension shall extend at least 20 inches in front of the fireplace opening if the opening is _____.\n\na. larger than 2 sq. ft\nb. larger than 4 sq. ft\nc. less than 6 sq. ft\nd. at least 6 sq. ft","answer":"d.","reference_1":"IRC 1001.10","reference_2":"IBC 2111.10","chapter":"09: Code Books"},"3040cf3f-9844-496c-85f4-7251c21d0c76":{"question":"Mineral surfaced roll roofing shall not be applied on roof slopes with less than ____ % slope.\n\na. 2%\nb. 8%\nc. 12%\nd. 33%","answer":"b.","reference_1":"IRC 905.5.2","reference_2":"IBC 1507.6.2","chapter":"09: Code Books"},"7a22ca7e-525a-4cd1-99d7-58bf04a5421e":{"question":"Clay tile shall be installed on a roof with a minimum slope of ____.\n\na. 2 1/2:12\nb. 3:12\nc. 4:12\nd. 5:12","answer":"a.","reference_1":"IRC 905.3.2","reference_2":"IBC 1507.3.2","chapter":"09: Code Books"},"86bd0aa3-d4aa-492c-a932-43d50493ad73":{"question":"The maximum allowed moisture content for lumber used to frame a 4:12 pitch roof:\n\na. 15%\nb. 19%\nc. 22%\nd. 27%","answer":"b.","reference_1":"IRC 802.1.3.8","reference_2":"IBC 2303.2.5","chapter":"09: Code Books"},"8fd7bf08-90b9-4276-a1bb-30867178f85f":{"question":"The minimum screw to attach steel sheets to metal framing (steel to steel) is\n\na. #5\nb. #6\nc. #7\nd. #8","answer":"d.","reference_1":"IRC 602.3.2","reference_2":"","chapter":"09: Code Books"},"20cb37d6-138f-426f-86cd-b4c84a8c730b":{"question":"One set of approved construction documents must be retained by the building official for not less than how many days from the date of the completion?\n\na. 90 days\nb. 180 days\nc. 30 days\nd. 120 days","answer":"b.","reference_1":"IRC 106.5","reference_2":"IBC 106.5","chapter":"09: Code Books"},"4cf5e230-233d-4832-a01e-498bd659bc66":{"question":"Where entry is made to a crawl space for services of utilities, foam plastic insulation shall be protected against ignition by ____ inch thick corrosion-resistant steel.\n\na. 0.024\nb. 0.016\nc. 0.25\nd. 0.033","answer":"b.","reference_1":"IRC 316.5.3","reference_2":"IBC 2603.4.1.6","chapter":"09: Code Books"},"1c629b7a-0655-47a9-827b-90dc2506792d":{"question":"A carport slab is to be installed in an area that is subject to severe weather conditions. The minimum compressive strength of the concrete to be used is ___ psi.\n\na. 2000\nb. 2500\nc. 3000\nd. 3500","answer":"d.","reference_1":"IRC Table 402.2","reference_2":"IBC Table 1904.2.2 (2)","chapter":"09: Code Books"},"907bd751-fdbf-4f86-8dc4-688844947c14":{"question":"The minimum flange width for a load-bearing cold-formed steel stud is ____ inches.\n\na. 1 1/2\nb. 1 5/8\nc. 1 3/4\nd. 2","answer":"b.","reference_1":"IRC Table 603.2(1)","reference_2":"","chapter":"09: Code Books"},"f274d274-7694-4b74-b657-68ce6ae36afc":{"question":"The minimum diameter head permitted to be on a fastener for asphalt shingles is _____\n\na. .105\"\nb. .375\"\nc. .50\"\nd. .75\"","answer":"b.","reference_1":"IRC 905.2.5","reference_2":"IBC 1507.2.6","chapter":"09: Code Books"},"de1d5e57-a8c8-446c-bab2-9885a3ef4336":{"question":"Which of the following statements is true regarding site plans submitted for demolition projects?\n\na. Site plans are not required for structures to be removed\nb. Site plan must show construction to be demolished\nc. Site plan must show the size and location of existing construction that will remain\nd. Both b and c are true","answer":"d.","reference_1":"IRC 106.2","reference_2":"IBC 106.2","chapter":"09: Code Books"},"591f7572-b959-4836-b885-aba8485caea3":{"question":"Reinforcing steel bars are placed within the tension zone to resist the tension and control the ____.\n\na. Compression\nb. Cracking\nc. Prestressing\nd. None of the above","answer":"b.","reference_1":"pg. 7","reference_2":"","chapter":"Post Tensioning (industrial and large commercial only)"},"6b151fbc-bfbf-4b2e-8fee-71af1824c4dc":{"question":"For encapsulated systems, efforts should be made to install the cap within ___ hours, but not more than 96 hours.\n\na. 10\nb. 12\nc. 24\nd. 30","answer":"c.","reference_1":"pg. 62","reference_2":"","chapter":"Post Tensioning (industrial and large commercial only)"},"0f45ed32-d371-4d88-b001-3cc47d3fe986":{"question":"In post-tensioned concrete, until the concrete hardens to about _____ percent, then tendon is not pulled.\n\na. 25\nb. 50\nc. 65\nd. 75","answer":"d.","reference_1":"pg. 8","reference_2":"","chapter":"Post Tensioning (industrial and large commercial only)"},"92653f07-3e7e-4e05-a91d-6c9c3891a2c0":{"question":"When troubleshooting monostrand equipment, if the pump is operating too slowly, what is the minimum amount of volts required for proper operation of the pump?\n\na. 110\nb. 120\nc. 220\nd. 240","answer":"a.","reference_1":"pg. 78","reference_2":"","chapter":"Post Tensioning (industrial and large commercial only)"},"4ff4717e-42a6-4cbf-96e1-be333edcd582":{"question":"Typically, for standard systems applications, a maximum of 1\" of exposed prestressing steel is allowed behind the stressing-end anchors and a maximum of ____ inches is allowed for fixed-end anchors?\n\na. 6\nb. 12\nc. 18\nd. 24","answer":"b.","reference_1":"pg. 36 Fig. 6-7","reference_2":"","chapter":"Post Tensioning (industrial and large commercial only)"},"c7678461-946b-4b6a-b0db-d543b2ec06f3":{"question":"What is the minimum cover between a wood form and a fixed-end anchor?\n\na. 1/2\"\nb. 3/4\"\nc. 1\"\nd. 2\"","answer":"c.","reference_1":"pg 36 Fig. 6-7","reference_2":"","chapter":"Post Tensioning (industrial and large commercial only)"},"93e3e7ea-ea5c-4c22-98fb-8cd6ce8d41b8":{"question":"Rock, sand, and void pockets in honeycomb concrete should be repaired prior to the stressing operation. Whose responsibility is it to repair this before the concrete is placed?\n\na. Employee\nb. Concractor\nc. The company that placed the concrete\nd. The engineer","answer":"c.","reference_1":"pg. 72","reference_2":"","chapter":"Post Tensioning (industrial and large commercial only)"},"ac4a1dcb-b5cf-4889-8a14-0ca3edc8c0a3":{"question":"One Kip is equal to ____ pounds of force.\n\na. 100\nb. 1000\nc. 1500\nd. 2000","answer":"b.","reference_1":"pg. 4","reference_2":"","chapter":"Post Tensioning (industrial and large commercial only)"},"affa7347-69f1-47da-88ea-414d3e5031e1":{"question":"Steel tendons are stressed ____ the concrete is placed.\n\na. before\nb. after\nc. during\nd. both a and b","answer":"d.","reference_1":"pg. 12","reference_2":"","chapter":"Post Tensioning (industrial and large commercial only)"},"965c8584-02d2-46d5-8888-9c0208878bba":{"question":"All of the following are advantages of post-tension prestressed concrete, except:\n\na. lower life cycle cost\nb. long economical spans\nc. watertight construction\nd. lower weight allows for increased seismic loading","answer":"d.","reference_1":"pg. 15","reference_2":"","chapter":"Post Tensioning (industrial and large commercial only)"},"177416b8-492e-4ba8-8ed4-176cc0f79a1c":{"question":"What is the vertical deviation or tolerance for elevated concrete with a depth of 8\"?\n\na. +/- 1/4\"\nb. +/- 3/8\"\nc. +/- 1/2\"\nd. +/- 1\"","answer":"a.","reference_1":"pg. 30","reference_2":"","chapter":"Post Tensioning (industrial and large commercial only)"},"a64cc868-228a-42a7-9201-fc4c2fa22b1a":{"question":"It is critical that an anchor be tightly secured perpendicular to the form by what minimum size nail?\n\na. 8d\nb. 16d\nc. 20d\nd. None of the above","answer":"c.","reference_1":"pg. 31","reference_2":"","chapter":"Post Tensioning (industrial and large commercial only)"},"03f8070b-6fa5-4662-9ea8-c6a6f5e4a1d0":{"question":"Any basic acceptable anchorage system must pass a static load test of ____ percent of the MUTS of the strand.\n\na. 75\nb. 80\nc. 95\nd. 100","answer":"c.","reference_1":"pg. 46","reference_2":"","chapter":"Post Tensioning (industrial and large commercial only)"},"b4f120ca-ae2d-4279-949d-7b7ae4b00551":{"question":"In preparation for stressing, when checking the stressing equipment, electric extension cords should be 3 wire, 12 gauge, and not over ____ feet in length.\n\na. 50\nb. 1000\nc. 150\nd. 200","answer":"b.","reference_1":"pg. 50","reference_2":"","chapter":"Post Tensioning (industrial and large commercial only)"},"1e7c0659-8e64-4149-a5b9-405a08781cf6":{"question":"To perform a \"lift-off\" you should start by opening the jack at least ____ inches, so that in case of wedge failure you do not get the jack hung-up.\n\na. 1\"\nb. 2\"\nc. 3\"\nd. 4\"","answer":"d.","reference_1":"pg. 76","reference_2":"","chapter":"Post Tensioning (industrial and large commercial only)"},"d28e4c3f-8f3b-442b-ab5b-913e97c8e71d":{"question":"Other than epoxy, what is another common type of coated reinforcing bar?\n\na. rubber\nb. zinc\nc. aluminum\nd. creasote","answer":"b.","reference_1":"pg. 18-1","reference_2":"","chapter":"Reinforcing Bars (industrial and large commercial only)"},"5fe60e3e-fd2c-4908-99d1-98ab20a3a2c0":{"question":"The MAXIMUM on-center spacing for reinforcing bars in a 6\" concrete slab:\n\na. 3\"\nb. 6\"\nc. 12\"\nd. 18\"","answer":"c.","reference_1":"pg. 11-5","reference_2":"","chapter":"Reinforcing Bars (industrial and large commercial only)"},"f93bcb54-7ae6-452e-b29b-0d4e87f25cb5":{"question":"The ____ is the load limit at which steel breaks.\n\na. compressive yield strength\nb. ultimate yield strength\nc. shear strength\nd. yield strength","answer":"b.","reference_1":"pg. 5 - 9","reference_2":"","chapter":"Reinforcing Bars (industrial and large commercial only)"},"3bc8c905-20cd-4b70-98ee-b881e459fe05":{"question":"What gauge wire is normally used for tying reinforcing bar?\n\na. #8\nb. #10\nc. #12\nd. #16","answer":"d.","reference_1":"pg. G-20","reference_2":"","chapter":"Reinforcing Bars (industrial and large commercial only)"},"95ea0d3a-d2c4-4d34-ba86-815d4d101207":{"question":"Which of the following is true regarding the length of splices of coated bars compared to uncoated bars?\n\na. shorter in length\nb. longer in length\nc. about the same\nd. none of the above","answer":"b.","reference_1":"pg. 18-4","reference_2":"","chapter":"Reinforcing Bars (industrial and large commercial only)"},"fded50b8-47a5-4e85-9bf2-e10d718b6066":{"question":"Standard rebar comes in what lengths?\n\na. 20'\nb. 40'\nc. 60'\nd. 80'","answer":"c.","reference_1":"pg. 10 - 12","reference_2":"","chapter":"Reinforcing Bars (industrial and large commercial only)"},"0eaf523f-0cec-4737-8e32-d54117687a6b":{"question":"If rust and light mill scale are present on reinforcing bars about to be placed, the contractor should:\n\na. ask for new bars to be delivered\nb. use the bars (condition is permitted)\nc. clean with oil and brush\nd. none of the above","answer":"b.","reference_1":"pg. 7-3","reference_2":"","chapter":"Reinforcing Bars (industrial and large commercial only)"},"87f4fcbc-3766-445a-ac09-f9f15b88f7f9":{"question":"What is the diameter of a #5 bar?\n\na. .375\nb. .5\nc. .625\nd. .750","answer":"c.","reference_1":"pg. 6-2","reference_2":"","chapter":"Reinforcing Bars (industrial and large commercial only)"},"6c577a69-b570-4663-9ddb-7c23c62345fb":{"question":"What is the maximum on-center spacing for beam bolsters?\n\na. 4'\nb. 5'\nc. 6'\nd. 8'","answer":"b.","reference_1":"pg. 12-3/13-3","reference_2":"","chapter":"Reinforcing Bars (industrial and large commercial only)"},"d567f362-c54d-45eb-bbc5-3b1ed11bbfa9":{"question":"Column dowels are often provided by ____ degree hooks, to provide a means of support where they rest on the footing mat.\n\na. 20\nb. 45\nc. 65\nd. 90","answer":"d.","reference_1":"pg. 11-7 / 12-6","reference_2":"","chapter":"Reinforcing Bars (industrial and large commercial only)"},"4f9203a9-98fa-4acc-8b8b-db9e1ec22dcd":{"question":"A beveled outside corner or edge on a beam or column is called a _______.\n\na. Choker\nb. Chamfer\nc. Cantilever\nd. None of the above","answer":"b.","reference_1":"pg. G-4 / G-5","reference_2":"","chapter":"Reinforcing Bars (industrial and large commercial only)"},"397eff06-ccdd-4b08-b9ec-9cb7e60a16a6":{"question":"Spot welding a bar at one point can reduce the strength of a bar up to ____ percent of its original capacity.\n\na. 30\nb. 40\nc. 50\nd. 60","answer":"b.","reference_1":"pg. 10-20 / 11-27","reference_2":"","chapter":"Reinforcing Bars (industrial and large commercial only)"},"a169a85b-d55b-4008-badb-bc7ad6c58970":{"question":"For lifting trusses with spans of 60' it is recommended that a spreader bar be used and attached to the top chords and webs at what intervals?\n\na. 5'\nb. 10'\nc. 15'\nd. 20'","answer":"b.","reference_1":"pg. 9","reference_2":"","chapter":"Wood Trusses (industrial and large commercial only)"},"9217f4e1-527b-4795-904f-029803b0795e":{"question":"During long term storage, care should be taken to protect the trusses against what?\n\na. Heat\nb. Moisture\nc. Flames\nd. Boring","answer":"b.","reference_1":"pg. 9","reference_2":"","chapter":"Wood Trusses (industrial and large commercial only)"},"55e02b93-8bdd-4965-8dff-da357b1663ea":{"question":"If trusses are to be stored horizontally, the blocking should be ____ to 10' centers or as required to prevent lateral bending?\n\na. Toe in\nb. Spread\nc. Toe out\nd. Fall horizontally","answer":"a.","reference_1":"pg. 8","reference_2":"","chapter":"Wood Trusses (industrial and large commercial only)"},"a45454e7-7a3f-4c2c-8c82-5b6c758c1b64":{"question":"Ground bracing should not be less than what grade of marked lumber?\n\na. 2 x 4\nb. 2 x 6\nc. 3 x 4\nd. 3 x 6","answer":"a.","reference_1":"pg. 19","reference_2":"","chapter":"Wood Trusses (industrial and large commercial only)"},"ed4d6cde-c151-49bc-9f73-29823e4ad321":{"question":"Temporary diagonal brace nailed to opposite side of web prevents lateral movement and should be repeated at approximately what foot intervals?\n\na. 5\nb. 10\nc. 15\nd. 20","answer":"d.","reference_1":"pg. 27","reference_2":"","chapter":"Wood Trusses (industrial and large commercial only)"},"ca45f886-ab7f-4145-9fcd-7737e4499181":{"question":"Any correction which involves cutting of any trusses is considered a major correction and should not be made without notifying whom?\n\na. a building official\nb. the owner\nc. a roofing contractor\nd. the truss manufacturer","answer":"d.","reference_1":"pg. 55","reference_2":"","chapter":"Wood Trusses (industrial and large commercial only)"},"58f80ab4-f8d2-42b9-bed5-e8f29a13e576":{"question":"Bottom chord lateral bracing may be applied to the top or underside of the chord member and should be nailed with a minimum of 2 ____ nails.\n\na. 8d\nb. 12d\nc. 16d\nd. 20d","answer":"c.","reference_1":"pg. 26","reference_2":"","chapter":"Wood Trusses (industrial and large commercial only)"},"885b1c92-96e0-469b-88c4-efac16fe122f":{"question":"Top chord bearing parallel chord trusses should have a maximum gap of ___ between the inside of the bearing and the first diagonal or vertical web?\n\na. 1/8\"\nb. 1/4\"\nc. 3/8\"\nd. 1/2\"","answer":"d.","reference_1":"pg. 11","reference_2":"","chapter":"Wood Trusses (industrial and large commercial only)"},"91a06f86-06ba-4736-b3fc-958faef32f01":{"question":"Trusses should not be installed with a variation from plumb at any point along the length of the truss from top to bottom chords which exceeds ____ of the depth.\n\na. 1/50\nb. 1/75\nc. 1/100\nd. 1/150","answer":"a.","reference_1":"pg. 11","reference_2":"","chapter":"Wood Trusses (industrial and large commercial only)"},"8bbf2aac-c666-45b0-8e2b-25d4e00800a5":{"question":"","answer":"","reference_1":"","reference_2":"","chapter":"Wood Trusses (industrial and large commercial only)"},"8aef2b0e-8f3a-4932-801a-7395a6a1a8d0":{"question":"The maximum usable strain at extreme concrete compression fiber shall be assumed to be equal to what?\n\na. 0.001\nb. 0.002\nc. 0.003\nd. 0.004","answer":"c.","reference_1":"ACI 381-14 22.2.2.1","reference_2":"","chapter":"ACI Practice Test"},"a68d0992-cd98-4d20-86f6-3d5b93c3e215":{"question":"Ducts for grouted single wire, single strand, or single bar or single bar tendons shall have an inside diameter at least ___ inch(es) larger than the pre-stressing steel diameter?\n\na. 1/8\nb. 1/4\nc. 1/2\nd. 1","answer":"b.","reference_1":"20.6.4.3","reference_2":"","chapter":"ACI Practice Test"},"c45d17ea-1f08-416c-953b-1d7774b12bcc":{"question":"Structural plain concrete walls shall be continuously supported by which of the following?\n\na. soil\nb. footings\nc. foundation walls\nd. all of the above","answer":"d.","reference_1":"14.1.3","reference_2":"","chapter":"ACI Practice Test"},"0f8c1a51-fcdb-4582-b584-ea1a2125582b":{"question":"Development length of individual bars within a bundle, in tension or compression, shall be that for the individual bar, increased by 33% for a ___ bar bundle?\n\na. 2\nb. 3\nc. 4\nd. 6","answer":"c.","reference_1":"25.3.1","reference_2":"","chapter":"ACI Practice Test"},"92c9e699-32fc-4eef-aaa4-47d86a7ca5e3":{"question":"In bars required for compression only, transmission of compression stress by bearing of square cut ends held in concentric contact by a suitable device shall?\n\na. be permitted\nb. be permitted only for #4 bars\nc. not be permitted\nd. not be permitted unless it has an engineers approval","answer":"a.","reference_1":"(d)","reference_2":"","chapter":"ACI Practice Test"},"4db3be9f-1380-4682-b9ac-bbc9a8659203":{"question":"Prestressing steel should not be stressed until the compressive strength of the concrete is at least ____ psi for multistrand tendons.\n\na. 2500\nb. 4000\nc. 3500\nd. 5000","answer":"b.","reference_1":"(j)","reference_2":"","chapter":"ACI Practice Test"},"e868bea4-afb5-4655-ba09-72d3b433172b":{"question":"The thickness of non-bearing walls shall not be less than 4 inches, nor less than ___ the least distance between members that provide lateral support.\n\na. 1/25\nb. 1/30\nc. 1/40\nd. 1/45","answer":"b.","reference_1":"Table 11.3.1.1","reference_2":"","chapter":"ACI Practice Test"},"9389d803-707d-4dde-b86f-cfd63a6f52a3":{"question":"According to ACI 318, what is the minimum thickness of exterior basement foundation walls?\n\na. 4\"\nb. 6\"\nc. 7.5\"\nd. 8.5\"","answer":"c.","reference_1":"14.3.1.1","reference_2":"","chapter":"ACI Practice Test"},"d8cf1db6-ff69-42dd-accd-9b7aa4a922ae":{"question":"When dealing with the strength of masonry, at each story level, at least ____ percent of the lateral stiffness shall be provided by lateral-force-resisting walls?\n\na. 50\nb. 60\nc. 80\nd. 95","answer":"c.","reference_1":"","reference_2":"","chapter":"ACI Practice Test"},"aac3d058-29ca-42fe-9ef7-92c189cca367":{"question":"What type of mortar shall be laid with a glass masonry unit?\n\na. Type S\nb. Type M\nc. Type O\nd. Type P","answer":"a.","reference_1":"13.6","reference_2":"","chapter":"ACI Practice Test"},"940134dd-24ab-4a86-851e-d3d73e389793":{"question":"According to ACI 530-05, which one of the following is NOT considered an anchor bolt in the allowable stress design of masonry?\n\na. Plate bolts\nb. Headed bolts\nc. J Bolts\nd. Headed bent-bar bolts","answer":"d.","reference_1":"","reference_2":"","chapter":"ACI Practice Test"},"7c84d700-7976-485a-afd3-8a1115022101":{"question":"Which of the following definitions best describes the words effective prestress?\n\na. prestressing tendon that is free to move laterally within the cross section of the member\nb. prestressing tendon that is not free to move laterally within the cross section of the member\nc. stress remaining in prestressing tendons after a gain has occurred\nd. stress remaining in prestressing tendons after all losses have occurred","answer":"d.","reference_1":"","reference_2":"","chapter":"ACI Practice Test"},"9b2c1259-b9e3-4492-a04a-1c3709bdb067":{"question":"Given: The average compressive stresses are based on the gross area using actual dimensions. For concentrated loads acting on the full wall thickness, the allowable stresses under the load may be increased by what percent?\n\na. 10\nb. 15\nc. 25\nd. 30","answer":"c.","reference_1":"","reference_2":"","chapter":"ACI Practice Test"},"30bb89e5-e3d0-4529-b6dc-bf5ebe093f6c":{"question":"A chimney shall not be corbelled more than ____ the chimney's wall thickness fram a wall.\n\na. .25\nb. .375\nc. .5\nd. .75","answer":"c.","reference_1":"IRC 1003.5","reference_2":"IBC 2113.5","chapter":"09: Code Books"},"1bf4c26b-5175-40a8-acdd-f025ec29a234":{"question":"Utility grade studs cannot be spaced more than ___ inches on center.\n\na. 12\nb. 16.\nc. 20\nd. 24","answer":"b.","reference_1":"IRC 603.3.1#1","reference_2":"IBC 2308.9.1","chapter":"09: Code Books"},"2a93e354-c5de-4481-b07f-af482f7e8cda":{"question":"To test the allowable triangular shaped opening created by the riser, tread, and bottom rail of a guard on an open stairway, a sphere ____ inches in diameter cannot pass through.\n\na. 4\nb. 6\nc. 8\nd. 10","answer":"b.","reference_1":"IRC 312.3","reference_2":"IBC 1013.3 Exception","chapter":"09: Code Books"},"225689f1-74c6-4f6d-ab82-7a8d5f56056c":{"question":"Untreated wood joists should not be installed closer than ___ inches.\n\na. 12\nb. 14\nc. 16\nd. 18","answer":"d.","reference_1":"IRC 317#1","reference_2":"IBC 2304.11.2.1","chapter":"09: Code Books"},"9ec355a1-bbb5-4c56-aa72-de265ec17ad5":{"question":"In residential structures, when there is usable space above and below the concealed space of a floor/ceiling assembly, draft stops must be installed so that the area of the concealed space does not exceed ___ square feet.\n\na. 500\nb. 800\nc. 1000\nd. 1200","answer":"c.","reference_1":"IRC 302.12","reference_2":"IBC 717.3.3","chapter":"09: Code Books"},"bd2a8f3d-4c10-460d-a5f8-b2a62ab61c56":{"question":"What is required when nailing a top plate to a stud?\n\na. 2 - 16d common\nb. 3 - 16d common\nc. 2 - 8d common\nd. 3 - 8d common","answer":"a.","reference_1":"IRC Table 602.3(1)","reference_2":"IBC Table 2304.9.1","chapter":"09: Code Books"},"3ebb1518-41f7-42cb-988a-23be9d951efe":{"question":"What is the maximum spacing of a 2 x 6 for a bearing wall to support a roof and ceiling only?\n\na. 16\" on center\nb. 20\" on center\nc. 24\" on center\nd. 28\" on center","answer":"c.","reference_1":"IRC Table 602.3(5)","reference_2":"IBC Table 2308.9.1","chapter":"09: Code Books"},"4f40e88a-28b6-4bd9-b57c-dc99faa75f22":{"question":"Beams and girders must bear at least ___ inch(es) on a masonry column.\n\na. 1\nb. 1 - 1/2\nc. 1 - 3/4\nd. 3","answer":"d3","reference_1":"IRC 502.6","reference_2":"IBC 2308.7","chapter":"09: Code Books"},"e043a578-77c7-4666-b5e6-582d8cf10f65":{"question":"For buildings with a roof pitch of less than ____, hips and valleys must be designed as beams.\n\na. 2:12\nb. 3:12\nc. 4:12\nd. 5:12","answer":"b.","reference_1":"IRC 802.3","reference_2":"IBC 2308.10","chapter":"09: Code Books"},"dfe6a05a-99d2-46a1-87da-266b1395941b":{"question":"Base flashing shall have a minimum thickness of ___ inches.\n\na. .016\nb. .017\nc. .018\nd. .019","answer":"d.","reference_1":"IRC 905.2.8.1","reference_2":"IBC 1507.2.9.1","chapter":"09: Code Books"},"04857163-6238-43ce-aee4-9ea145326c1a":{"question":"Footings for masonry fireplaces shall extend at least ____ inches beyond the face of the fireplace.\n\na. 4\"\nb. 6\"\nc. 10\"\nd. 12\"","answer":"b.","reference_1":"IRC 1003.2","reference_2":"IBC 2111.2","chapter":"09: Code Books"},"2b95778a-c22f-4f52-b73f-b872645c75bd":{"question":"What is the minimum required headroom (unobstructed) in the attic space above the access opening?\n\na. 30\"\nb. 36\"\nc. 48\"\nd. 72\"","answer":"a.","reference_1":"IRC 807.1","reference_2":"IBC 1209.2","chapter":"09: Code Books"},"159b2a61-1be9-45cc-89b5-063638008487":{"question":"Without approval from a registered design professional, which of the following jobsite modifications can be made to wood floor trusses?\n\nac cut\nb. spliced\nc. notched\nd. none of the above","answer":"d.","reference_1":"IRC 502.11.3","reference_2":"IBC 2303.4.1.7","chapter":"09: Code Books"},"582bf359-d284-47cc-a4f6-2766b298e9be":{"question":"What is the maximum notch depth allowed for a 2 x 12 nominal floor joist?\nNote: The joist spans 14'6\" and the notch needs to be made 5' from one end.\n\na. 1 - 7/8\"\nb. 1 - 3/4\"\nc. 2\"\nd. None of the above","answer":"d.","reference_1":"IRC 502.8.1","reference_2":"IBC 2303.4.1.7","chapter":"09: Code Books"},"91411dad-9f29-4757-a0d5-adb43cd63033":{"question":"Holes bored in a floor joist to install plumbing pipes should not be placed closer than ____ from the top.\n\na. Two times the thickness of the pipe\nb. 2 inches\nc. One half the joist depth\nd. None of the above","answer":"b.","reference_1":"IRC 502.8.1","reference_2":"IBC 2308.8.2","chapter":"09: Code Books"},"10ab104f-3e0f-4805-a69e-75bcbef44e9a":{"question":"","answer":"","reference_1":"IRC ","reference_2":"IBC ","chapter":"09: Code Books"},"5811878f-1319-4ce2-bf97-14d13b588275":{"question":"The allowable foundation (load bearing pressure in pounds per square foot for sedimentary and foliated backfill is:\n\na. 2,000\nb. 3,000\nc. 4,000\nd. 12,000","answer":"c.","reference_1":"IRC Table 401.4.1","reference_2":"IBC Table 1804.2","chapter":"09: Code Books"},"4ddc502a-c292-492f-b764-8264d1c34331":{"question":"A guardrail system is required for protection when a porch or balcony is located more than ____ inches above the grade or floor below.\n\na. 24\nb. 30\nc. 36\nd. 40","answer":"b.","reference_1":"IRC 312.1","reference_2":"IBC 1013.1","chapter":"09: Code Books"},"54e3f978-39b1-42b7-8786-fc0c4edcc5b2":{"question":"Which of the following construction projects would NOT require a building permit?\n\na. 400 square feet, two story\nb. One story, 200 square feet attached to an existing two car garage\nc. A one story detached accessory structure with 190 square feet\nd. None of the above","answer":"c.","reference_1":"IRC 105.2","reference_2":"IBC 105.2#1","chapter":"09: Code Books"},"702f5834-c419-43df-9816-bce0addfc818":{"question":"What size and type gypsum board is required to separate a garage from a habitable room located above it?\n\na. 1/2\" Type X\nb. 5/8\" Type X\nc. 3/4\" Type X\nd. 3/16\" Type X","answer":"b.","reference_1":"IRC 302.6","reference_2":"IBC 406.1.4","chapter":"09: Code Books"},"274c09c4-05c9-4b90-a818-542cebc18158":{"question":"A notch made at the end of a floor joist should not exceed ___ the depth of the joist.\n\na. 1/3\nb. 1/4\nc. 1/6\nd. 1/2","answer":"b.","reference_1":"IRC 502.8.1","reference_2":"IBC 2308.8.2","chapter":"09: Code Books"},"fe861daa-d757-4a20-bef6-1efb93da78c0":{"question":"What is the maximum span for a 2 x 8 nominal floor joist (Southern pine #2) to be installed in a sleeping area? Note: Dead load is 10 psf, joists will be installed 16\" on center\n\na. 10'9\"\nb. 14'2\"\nc. 13'6\"\nd. 13'3\"","answer":"b.","reference_1":"IRC Table 502.3.1(1)","reference_2":"IBC Table 2308.8(1)","chapter":"09: Code Books"},"05f8b748-97c4-4e9b-8018-e93f4455f316":{"question":"A hole may not be bored closer than ___ inches to the edge of a stud located in an exterior load-bearing framed wall.\n\na. 1/4\nb. 1/2\nc. 3/4\nd. 5/8","answer":"d.","reference_1":"IRC 602.6","reference_2":"IBC 2308.9.11","chapter":"09: Code Books"},"5fd96089-e673-45c6-9f4a-7b8442bda018":{"question":"Interior partitions (nonbearing) may be constructed with at least a ___ top plate.\n\na. Double top plate\nb. Single top plate\nc. Double top plate if wall height exceeds 10'\nd. None of the above","answer":"b.","reference_1":"IRC 602.5","reference_2":"IBC 2308.9.2.3","chapter":"09: Code Books"},"092d33ab-b6d6-4d80-a824-6a0d2216a1f2":{"question":"A listed flame spread index of ___ or less is required when codes specify fire-retardant-treated wood.\n\na. 15\nb. 20\nc. 25\nd. 30","answer":"c.","reference_1":"IRC 802.1.3","reference_2":"IBC 2303.2","chapter":"09: Code Books"},"67bee7b9-30f8-4441-82a4-a058e23c36c5":{"question":"What is the minimum head lap allowed for slate shingles secured to a roof with 6:12 slope?\n\na. 1\"\nb. 2\"\nc. 3\"\nd. 4\"","answer":"d.","reference_1":"IRC 905.6.5 table","reference_2":"IBC 1507.7.5 table","chapter":"09: Code Books"}}
